Hi, this time I'm going to show you the elements of
the view menu. Some of the element of the view menu of Padre.
What you can see here is 0.84 version of Padre, in your version it might be slightly different.
And what you see in this editor is the main script of Padre itself
So, if you go to the view menu, there are couple of entries, that are interesting.
For example there is a show line numbers, these are basic things.
Show you the line numbers on left hand side.
Or there is the current line
that puts this yellow line in the editor
at the beginning when I started to use this, I did not like it,
but now I got quite used to it and I prefer because it
make easier for me to recognize where the cursor is currently.
Then there is the project browser, sorry the project browser
Which opens window of left hand side.
If you open the file in Padre, a Perl file,
it will automatically traverse the directory structure and look for some kind of indication of a project, a Perl project
So the indications could be eiter a Makefile.PL, that you see here, or a Build.PL or the ini file of the dist-zilla distributor
Or if you don't have any of those some reason
which would not be really good, but if you don't have them, then you can just create an empty Padre.yml file
and whenever Padre finds that, it will assume that this is the root directory of your project
and then you can see the whole project here
that is both for this ... showing the directory here and for some other items in Padre
If you go to the lib directory and then we can open one of the files at the Padre.pm, which is the main module of Padre.
Going back to the View menu, I can click on the Show functions,
it will open a window on the right hand side that show all the functions that are defined,
functions or methods, because there might be just methods in the object oriented module
So all the functions that are defined in the current file
You can click on either of these but when you double click on one of the entries
Padre will automatically jump to the definition of that subroutine.
Here in a top, there is a filter so I can start typing in letters
and if filter the functions that will show only the functions that have that letter or 'e', 'c' letters in the name
That's the function, I can close it here.
The other things on the right-hand side which is as interesting is Outline entry
It's a more heavy weight tool to do similar things so it will parse your current file
and show what pragmatas you are using, so 'strict' or 'warnings' and stuff like this
what modules are used in this code, and what methods are there, that we saw earlier.
Here you actually click on that item and it automatically will jump, show to that part of editor of the file
or you can right click on one of them and then go to element is the thing you saw earlier jumping to the
actually usage of the pragmata or the module.
or you can click on the open documentation and you will see the documentation of that specific pragmata
or if you go to this module, let's say, this one,
and than open documentation, and you will see the documentation of that module
So, that's what you can have for the outline view.
Another entry, here is the output window which is at the bottom of the screen
that, what is interesting, is automatically opened
whenever something needs it. For example, when you run a script, what might happen
Then there is a syntax check, which is an important tool
It opens and it takes some time, because it actually checks if the syntax is correct for its file.
But then if you start typing in some code like this, then it will automatically check the syntax of the current file.
You can see that it gives you the error message here.
If you click on the entry then it will give you some more further description of the diagnostic basically.
And then the double click on the error actually let you jump to the place here
you have it for example, if I just type in "my" here, then it will tell me if is it error or is it correct, the syntax is correct.
So that's the syntax check and that is pretty useful for people to see that all the time.
And here there are the new lines, so you can see what kind of new lines you have, which may help sometimes
Or you can see the white spaces here or tabs of the actual spaces here. These the things that you can see
Then the Call Tips. So let's turn this on but let's turn other things off because I don't really white spaces I don't really like here and new lines
So let's say I start to type in sub-string and then when I get full name of the subroutine
and then it will show me a call-tip here
Showing small description of what kind of parameters that subroutine can have or little description of the subroutine.
So that basically the simple presentation that I've shown you now.
Will see what other stuff we can see in the next edition of this screencasts.
Thank you for listening, and watching. Bye bye.